Contact

daverosetholley@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/daverose-tholley-915a7b151 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Front-end Development Research Android Studio

Certifications

Provist List (1st | 3rd | 4th Year)
National Female Pre-Tech Training
Program
Lancaster Award (Gold)

Publications

Ethnography Report: COVID-19 Pandemic With Regards to Peoples' Reaction and the Future Development of Interactive Systems

Daverose Tholley

Software Engineer (Trainee) at ENYATA Accra

Summary

I have completed my BSc (Hons) in Computer Science from Lancaster University Ghana where I was obtained a First Class and I was a recipient of the Lancaster Award. During the course of my academic career, I learned the importance of applying the principles of Computer Science to modern computing strategies from experts in the field. Recently, I completed my dissertation on the development of a time management application for students, where I implemented these principles to provide a working application to aid students to manage and prioritize their time.

I have also accrued nearly 1 year of work experience. Contributions to my current and former roles, research opportunities, and this field at large revolve around my essential talents in data cleaning, data analysis, Web and app development, and research.

Experience

Enyata

Software Engineer (Trainee) October 2021 - Present (5 months)

Accra, Greater Accra, Ghana

Currently in the training program called 'The Academy'. The idea of the Academy is to groom developers in software engineering for weeks, where the end goal is to achieve three things from the trainee: quality of service, character, and speed of execution.

West Africa Civil Society Institute (WACSI)
Data Migration Analyst
June 2021 - July 2021 (2 months)
Accra, Greater Accra, Ghana

- Review data uploaded by the organization and identify, analyze, interpret trends or patterns in the data sets.
- I create a backup of all registered organizations' accounts across 18 African countries in English and French from the old website to the new upgraded version

- Also, I create a backup of all videos and images on the old platform in English and French
- Create a comprehensive report to record every discrepancy and inconsistency as errors to be addressed later.
- In addition to my academic and research experiences, my work at WACSI afforded me the opportunity to gain professional practice in the organization and informative coordination of civil society and non governmental organizations funded projects through fulfilling diverse administrative tasks.

Statistics Sierra Leone

Data Cleaner | 2019 SIERRA LEONE DEMOGRAPHIC AND HEALTH SURVEY (SLDHS)

June 2019 - September 2019 (4 months)

Freetown, Sierra Leone

- Using CSPro 6.3 with proper supervision, I had to use problem-solving skills to remove and/or amend resolving all discrepancies and inconsistencies thereby producing clean data for better decision making
- By being thorough and effective, I helped lessen the burden and workload on my partner/ supervisor, therefore, increasing the work pace and greatly decreasing the number of discrepancies to be resolved

Research Center for Development in Science and Technology SL Ltd

Front-End Website Developer & Data Entry Operator July 2018 - September 2018 (3 months)

Freetown, Sierra Leone

- I created their first-ever website, increasing their accessibility, thereby allowing them to reach a wider audience online, gaining more clients
- I was tasked to store all data collected from the survey on customer feedback of our client's business and clean errors. By doing this, the research analyst was enriched with clean data to perform an accurate SWOT analysis on the client's business thereby helping them cash in on their strengths

Education

Lancaster University Ghana
Bachelor's degree (Hons), Computer Science · (2017 - 2021)